dnaindia.com 2018-12-12

# DNA India: Latest News Headlines, Breaking News & Live Updates on Politics, Business, Sports, Bollywood

carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing, chargeback and collection. 

  * We may also use your information to contact you about our own and third-party services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please provide explicit consent for the same when we collect your data and/or adjust your user preferences in your account profile concerning your choices/preferences provided. 

## Disclosure to third parties

### General Disclosure

At times the dnaindia.com may make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with the dnaindia.com to provide service, or that help the dnaindia.com market to customers. For example, when you purchase and activate subscription, you authorize the dnaindia.com to exchange the information you provide during the activation process to carry out a service. If you are approved for service, your account will be governed by the dnaindia.com’s privacy policy. Personal information will only be shared by the dnaindia.com to provide or improve our service and marketing aspects; it will not be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes.

We do not share your personal information with Companies, organizations, or individuals outside of dnaindia.com except in the following cases:

### Promotional Offers

We’ll share or disclose your personal information outside of dnaindia.com when we have your consent. For example, providing E-mail related services such as marketing newsletters, promotions and offers.

### Business Transfers

We provide personal information to our affiliates and other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. For example, we use service providers to help us with customer support.

### Legal

In the event of any requirement by court order, government or quasi-government agency to disclose Your Personal Information, We will disclose information as may be legally required. We may also disclose Your Personal Information if we, in the good faith believe that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process.

In the event dnaindia.com is merged with or acquired by another company, we and our affiliates may share your personal information, wholly or in part, with another business entity.

## Your Controls and Choices

We provide you the ability to exercise certain controls and choices regarding our collection, use and sharing of your personal information. In accordance with applicable law, your controls and choices may include:

### Managing Your Information

You can access and update some of your personal information through your account settings. If you have chosen to connect your dnaindia.com account to a third-party application, like Facebook, Google or Twitter, you can change your settings and remove permission for the app by changing your account settings. You are responsible for keeping your personal information up-to-date. The dnaindia.com will send you periodic reminders via e-mail to maintain the accuracy of your personal information.

### Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Information

You can ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information concerning you (this is the information which you cannot update yourself within your dnaindia.com account) by sending us an e-mail

### Data Retention and Erasure

We retain your personal information as long as necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your information then you can request that we erase your personal information and close your dnaindia.com account. Please note that if your request for the erasure of your personal information;

    * We may retain some of your personal information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention and enhancing safety. For example, if we suspend a dnaindia.com account for fraud or safety reasons, we may retain certain information from that account to prevent that user from opening a new account in the future.
    * We may retain and use your personal information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations. For example, we may keep some of your information for tax, legal reporting and auditing obligations.
    * Because we maintain copies of the dnaindia.com to protect from accidental or malicious loss and destruction, residual copies of your personal information may not be removed from our backup systems for a limited period of time.

### Withdrawing Consent and Restriction of Processing

For withdrawing your consent at any time during the tenure of your services with us, you may choose to do so by sending us an e-mail. We shall review your request and may ask you to verify your identity. Post verification we will withdraw the consent for which request was made by you and stop any further processing of your personal information

### Objection to Processing

Where your personal information is processed for direct marketing purposes, you may, at any time ask us to cease processing your data for these direct marketing purposes by sending an e-mail to us.

### Complaints

You can write to our data protection officer in case of any grievance or compliant. You have the right to complaint about the data processing activities carried out by dnaindia.com before the competent data protection authorities.

Please be aware that if you do not allow us to collect personal information from you, we may not be able to deliver certain experiences, products, and services to you, and some of our services may not be able to take account of your interests and preferences. If collection of personal information is mandatory, we will make that clear at the point of collection so that you can make an informed decision whether to participate. If you have questions about the specific personal information about you that we process or retain, and your rights regarding that personal information, please contact our customer support team

## Children’s Privacy

dnaindia.com is not intentionally designed for or directed at persons less than 16 years of age. dnaindia.com does not knowingly permit any person who is under 16 years of age to register with the services or to provide any other personally identifying information. If dnaindia.com becomes aware that any personally identifiable information of persons less than 16 years of age has been collected on the dnaindia.com without verified parental consent, then dnaindia.com will take the appropriate steps to delete any such information and notify the parent.

However, we consider it the responsibility of parents to monitor their children’s use of our services. Nevertheless, it is our policy not to collect and process any personal information from children below 16 years of age or offer to send any promotional materials to persons in that category.

dnaindia.com does not seek or intend to seek or receive any personal information from children. Should a parent or guardian have reasons to believe that a minor has provided dnaindia.com with personal information without their prior consent, please contact our customer support team to ensure that the personal information is removed from the dnaindia.com.

## Data transfer, storage & processing globally

We operate globally and may transfer your personal information to individual companies of the dnaindia.com affiliated companies or third parties in locations around the world for the purposes described in this privacy policy. Wherever your personal information is transferred, stored or processed by us, we will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. Additionally, when using or disclosing personal information transferred from the European Union, we use standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, adopt other means under European Union law for ensuring adequate safeguards.

## Security and compliance with laws

We are continuously implementing and updating administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your information against unauthorized access, loss, destruction, or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use to protect your information are firewalls and data encryption, and information access controls. If you know or have reason to believe that your dnaindia.com account credentials have been lost, stolen, altered, or otherwise compromised or in case of any actual or suspected unauthorized use of your account, please contact us by contacting our customer support team.

## Change in Policy

This Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to modify the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to ensure compliance with applicable laws (“Updated Terms”). The Updated Terms shall be effective immediately and shall supersede these the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will not be under an obligation to notify you of any changes to this privacy policy except if the changes made to the policy significantly affects your rights or as may be required by law. You shall be solely responsible for reviewing the Privacy Policy from time to time for any modifications. By continuing to use dnaindia.com after the updated Terms have been published, you affirm your agreement to the updated terms.

## Contact information

### I. Support

If you require any information or clarification regarding the use of your personal information or this privacy policy or grievances with respect to use of your personal information, please email us at [response@zeemedia.esselgroup.com](mailto:response@zeemedia.esselgroup.com)

### II. Data Controller Officer

If you have any queries, complaints regarding the collecting, processing, transfer of personal data/information or regarding this policy please contact us at [response@zeemedia.esselgroup.com.](mailto:response@zeemedia.esselgroup.com)
